Richard S. Latham Papers
Richard S. Latham Papers
1958-1967
Latham, Richard S.
14.0 linear ft.
Papers of the American industrial designer. Correspondence, expense files, diaries.
149123
Biographical History
Richard Latham (1920-1991) was an American industrial designer.
Latham was born in Kansas City and studied at the Art Institute of Chicago. His first job was as an industrial designer for Montgomery Ward. During the war he worked for a model shop building models and mockups of military products, including the first instrument panels for radar and for jet fighters. In 1945 he took a position with the Chicago office of Raymond Loewy, where he entered the then-new field of corporate imaging and branding, designing a complete "look" (packaging, logos, advertising, etc.) for clients ranging from International Harvester to Frigidaire to meat-packing giant Armour.
Latham eventually became Director of Design for Loewy's Chicago office, but in 1955 he left to open Latham, Tyler, and Jensen. The new firm focused on product planning, which was at the time a relatively new field. Their first large client was General Electric's Major Appliance Group in Louisville; later they added GE's consumer electronics group. The company was successful to open a branch office in Denmark.
In 1965 Latham became President of the International Council of Societies of Industrial Designers, whose members societies come from 40 countries; in this position he travelled, lectured, and met with designers from all over the world. Speaking a few years later, he said:
What has become a prominent question in my mind is, "Is all this design necessary or literally are all these things necessary?" I've been told that the design staff at General Motors as of 1969 is 1,700 men...[and] that in 1969...the four major television companies will completely restyle their product lines, in effect duplicating each others product...The question that occurs to me is are all of these exact copies of each other necessary, and finally, the question is, "is an Early American television set necessary?"...If LTJ had not pursued the planning philosophy I probably wouldn't be asking myself these kind of questions, but rather concentrating on the next client and all the next things that we should design whether the world needs them or not.
In 1970 Latham opened Richard S. Latham & Associates, Inc. He became design advisor for Bang & Olufsen of Denmark, and for Land's End, which he helped found. Shortly after his retirement, Latham said:
I find I have not changed my opinion of the fundamental rights and wrongs attendant to the practice of my profession and the succeeding years seem to have demonstrated the inherent problems of "marketing too many" low quality products to ordinary citizens; "junk food" has become a part of the American language in that time period, and the excesses of high pressure marketing and low quality products and service have come to be understood at every walk of life in the USA today.
[Portions of this biographical sketch adapted from the biographical sketch on the IDSA's website, and the autobiographical essay in the collection. Quotes are taken from the essay in the collection.]
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The Richard Latham Papers are arranged in five categories.
Financial papers consists of invoices canceled over a four year period. Client correspondence refers to correspondence with Latham's business clients; among the companies represented are Archer Daniels Midland, Blackhawk Manufacturing, Celotex Corporation, Chicago Tribune, Culligan, General Electric, Hammond Organ, Kuehne Manufacturing, Playskool, Simplicity, and U.S. Steel. General correspondence contains correspondence to various persons concerning non-business topics. Expense files contains material relating to business and personal expenses, 1966-1968. Diaries discuss Latham's trip to the Berlin Fair in 1962.
Arrangement of the Collection
Financial papers are subdivided by year into four series (1965-1968 inclusive); within that material is arranged alphabetically. Client correspondence is arranged alphabetically. General correspondence, expense files, and diaries are arranged chronologically.
Related Material
has numerous collections of individuals and organizations in the field of industrial design. Please refer to for a complete listing.
Subject and Genre Headings
Industrial Design; Latham, Richard S.; Industrial design -- United States.; Industrial designers -- United States.; Correspondence.; Invoices.; Diaries.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Inventory
- Financial
  - 1965
    - A, miscellaneous (Box 1)
    - American Airlines (Box 1)
    - American Express (Box 1)
    - American Society of Industrial Designers (Box 1)
    - Arrow Photo Copy (Box 1)
    - Avis Rent-A-Car (Box 1)
    - B, miscellaneous (Box 1)
    - Barret-Schiristie Co. (Box 1)
    - Berkshire Hotel (Box 1)
    - Browne and Storch (Box 1)
    - Brundo Art Supply (Box 1)
    - C, miscellaneous (Box 1)
    - Cadillac Plastic (Box 1)
    - Central Steel and Wire (Box 1)
    - John Sheffield Chapman (Box 1)
    - Chez Paul (Box 1)
    - Chicago Paper Company (Box 1)
    - Chicago Towel Company (Box 1)
    - Clark and Barlow (Box 1)
    - Commonwealth Edison Company (Box 1)
    - Container Corporation of America (Box 1)
    - Continental Coffee Company (Box 1)
    - Cordcraft, Inc. (Box 1)
    - Craftman Type (Box 1)
    - David Cramer (Box 1)
    - D, miscellaneous (Box 1)
    - The Drake (Box 1)
    - DuBow Secretarial Service (Box 1)
    - E, miscellaneous (Box 1)
    - Emery Air Freight Corporation (Box 1)
    - F, miscellaneous (Box 1)
    - Fey Publishing Company (Box 1)
    - G, miscellaneous (Box 1)
    - Gaslight Club (Box 1)
    - General Fireproofing Company (Box 1)
    - Grand Prix Automotive (Box 1)
    - H, miscellaneous (Box 1)
    - Harry's Auto Parts (Box 1)
    - Fred Harvey (Box 1)
    - Paul J. Heinz (Box 1)
    - Hertz Rent-A-Car (Box 1)
    - Hinckley and Schmitt (Box 1)
    - Edward Hines Lumber (Box 1)
    - Holmes Company (Box 1)
    - Horders (Box 1)
    - Barry Howe (Box 1)
    - Huey Company (Box 1)
    - I, miscellaneous (Box 1)
    - Illinois Bell Telephone (Box 1)
    - Illinois Central Railroad (Box 1)
    - Illustro Inc. (Box 1)
    - International Business Machines (Box 1)
    - K, miscellaneous (Box 1)
    - Kelley and Smith (Box 1)
    - Kennedy Webster (Box 1)
    - Keuffel and Esser (Box 1)
    - The Key Club (Box 1)
    - Kroch's and Brentano's (Box 1)
    - Borris Kroll Fabrics, Inc. (Box 1)
    - L, miscellaneous (Box 2)
    - LaSalle National Bank (Box 2)
    - Lettering, Inc. (Box 2)
    - M, miscellaneous (Box 2)
    - Monsen, 2 folders (Box 2)
    - Fritz Mulhauser (Box 2)
    - N, miscellaneous (Box 2)
    - National Rent-A-Car (Box 2)
    - National Rent-A-Car or Truck (Box 2)
    - Near North Guide (Box 2)
    - Nu Way Express and Van Company, Inc. (Box 2)
    - O, miscellaneous (Box 2)
    - The Odman Corporation (Box 2)
    - OMNI-Division (Box 2)
    - Ozark Airlines (Box 2)
    - P, miscellaneous (Box 2)
    - Package Design (Box 2)
    - Bruce Pattou (Box 2)
    - Pure Oil Company (Box 2)
    - Railway Express Agency (Box 2)
    - Runkle, Thompson, Kovats, Inc. (Box 2)
    - S, miscellaneous (Box 2)
    - Louis Sappanos Company (Box 2)
    - Schumacher Ford, Inc. (Box 2)
    - Sheldon's Art and Drafting Co. (Box 2)
    - Standard Oil Company, 2 folders (Box 2)
    - Standard Photo (Box 2)
    - Standard Studios (Box 2)
    - T, miscellaneous (Box 2)
    - Bill Taura Design (Box 2)
    - Joanne Taylor (Box 2)
    - U, miscellaneous (Box 2)
    - V, miscellaneous (Box 2)
    - W, miscellaneous (Box 2)
    - Walroth Whiteprint Equipment (Box 2)
    - Joseph Welna (Box 2)
    - Western Union (Box 2)
    - The Whitehall Club (Box 2)
    - XYZ, miscellaneous (Box 2)
    - Z Frank Rent a Car (Box 2)
    - Contribution Receipt File (Box 2)
  - 1966
    - A, miscellaneous (Box 3)
    - American Airlines (Box 3)
    - American Express (Box 3)
    - Arrow Photo, 2 folders (Box 3)
    - Avis Rent-a-Car (Box 3)
    - B, miscellaneous (Box 3)
    - Browne and Storch (Box 3)
    - Brundo Art Supply Company (Box 3)
    - C, miscellaneous (Box 3)
    - Cadillac Plastic (Box 3)
    - John Sheffield Chapman (Box 3)
    - Chez Paul (Box 3)
    - Chicago Towel Company (Box 3)
    - Clark and Barlow (Box 3)
    - Commonwealth Edison Company (Box 3)
    - Container Corporation of America (Box 3)
    - Continental Coffee Company (Box 3)
    - David Cramer (Box 3)
    - D, miscellaneous (Box 3)
    - The Drake (Box 3)
    - DuBow Secretarial Service (Box 3)
    - E, miscellaneous (Box 3)
    - Emery Air Freight (Box 3)
    - F, miscellaneous (Box 3)
    - G, miscellaneous (Box 3)
    - Gaslight Club (Box 3)
    - H, miscellaneous (Box 3)
    - Harry's Auto Parts (Box 3)
    - Fred Harvey (Box 3)
    - Hertz Rent-A-Car (Box 3)
    - Holmes Company (Box 3)
    - Horders (Box 3)
    - Barry Howe (Box 3)
    - Huey Company (Box 3)
    - I, miscellaneous (Box 3)
    - Illinois Bell Telephone (Box 3)
    - Illinois Central Railroad (Box 3)
    - International Business Machines (Box 3)
    - K, miscellaneous (Box 3)
    - Kelley Ambruse and Smith (Box 3)
    - Kennedy Webster (Box 3)
    - The Key Club (Box 3)
    - Kinney Rent-A-Car (Box 3)
    - Kroch's and Brentano's (Box 3)
    - L, miscellaneous (Box 3)
    - LaSalle National Bank (Box 3)
    - Lettering, Inc. (Box 3)
    - Logan Square Typographers (Box 3)
    - M, miscellaneous (Box 3)
    - McClurg Company, A.G. (Box 3)
    - McFarland (Box 3)
    - Merit Photo Company (Box 3)
    - Monsen Typographers, 2 folders (Box 3)
    - Mulhauser, Fritz (Box 3)
    - N, miscellaneous (Box 4)
    - Near North Guild (Box 4)
    - O, miscellaneous (Box 4)
    - Odman Corporation (Box 4)
    - Old Wells Auto Park (Box 4)
    - P, miscellaneous (Box 4)
    - Postmaster of Chicago (Box 4)
    - Pure Oil Company (Box 4)
    - R, miscellaneous, 2 folders (Box 4)
    - Railway Express Agency (Box 4)
    - Runkle, Thompson, Kovats, Inc. (Box 4)
    - Frederick Ryder Company (Box 4)
    - S, miscellaneous (Box 4)
    - Sheldon's, 3 folders (Box 4)
    - Standard Oil Company, 3 folders (Box 4)
    - Standard Photo Company (Box 4)
    - T, miscellaneous (Box 4)
    - Joanne Taylor (Box 4)
    - U, miscellaneous (Box 4)
    - W, miscellaneous (Box 4)
    - Walruth Whiteprint Company (Box 4)
    - Welna Gallery (Box 4)
    - Western Union (Box 4)
    - Raymond Wielgus Company (Box 4)
    - XYZ, miscellaneous (Box 4)
  - 1967
    - A, miscellaneous (Box 4)
    - American Airlines (Box 4)
    - American Express (Box 4)
    - Arrow Photo Copy, 4 folders (Box 4)
    - Avis Rent-A-Car (Box 4)
    - B, miscellaneous, 2 folders (Box 4)
    - Browne and Storch (Box 5)
    - The Brundo Art Supply Co. (Box 5)
    - C, miscellaneous (Box 5)
    - Cadillac Plastic (Box 5)
    - John Sheffield Chapman (Box 5)
    - Chez Paul (Box 5)
    - Chicago Towel Company (Box 5)
    - Clark and Barlow (Box 5)
    - Commonwealth Edison Co. (Box 5)
    - Continental Coffee Company (Box 5)
    - D, miscellaneous (Box 5)
    - The Drake (Box 5)
    - DuBow Secretarial (Box 5)
    - E, miscellaneous (Box 5)
    - Emery Air Freight (Box 5)
    - F, miscellaneous (Box 5)
    - G, miscellaneous (Box 5)
    - Robert J. Gary (Box 5)
    - Gaslight Club (Box 5)
    - H, miscellaneous (Box 5)
    - Harry's Auto Parts (Box 5)
    - Fred Harvey (Box 5)
    - Hertz Rent-A-Car (Box 5)
    - Hinckley and Schmidt (Box 5)
    - Horders (Box 5)
    - Barry Howe (Box 5)
    - Huey Company (Box 5)
    - I, miscellaneous (Box 5)
    - Illinois Bell Telephone Co. (Box 5)
    - Illinois Central Railroad (Box 5)
    - International Business Machines (Box 5)
    - K, miscellaneous (Box 5)
    - The Key Club (Box 5)
    - Kinney Rent-A-Car (Box 5)
    - Kroch's and Brentano's (Box 5)
    - L, miscellaneous (Box 5)
    - LaSalle National Bank (Box 5)
    - Lettering, Inc. (Box 5)
    - Logan Square Typographers (Box 5)
    - M, miscellaneous, 2 folders (Box 5)
    - Merit Photo, 2 folders (Box 5)
    - Monsen Typographers, 2 folders (Box 5)
    - Fritz Mulhauser (Box 5)
    - N, miscellaneous (Box 5)
    - O, miscellaneous (Box 5)
    - Odman Corporation (Box 5)
    - Old Wells Auto Park (Box 5)
    - P, miscellaneous (Box 5)
    - Post Master of Chicago (Box 5)
    - Pure Oil Company (Box 5)
    - R, miscellaneous (Box 6)
    - Railway Express Agency (Box 6)
    - Fredrick Ryder Company (Box 6)
    - S, miscellaneous (Box 6)
    - Sheldon's (Box 6)
    - Standard Oil Company (Box 6)
    - Standard Photo Supply (Box 6)
    - T, miscellaneous (Box 6)
    - Joanne Taylor (Box 6)
    - United Airlines (Box 6)
    - W, miscellaneous (Box 6)
    - Walruth Whiteprint Equipment (Box 6)
    - Welna Gallery (Box 6)
    - Western Union (Box 6)
    - Raymond Wielgus Products (Box 6)
    - XYZ, miscellaneous (Box 6)
  - 1968
    - A, miscellaneous (Box 6)
    - American Airlines, 2 folders (Box 6)
    - American Express (Box 6)
    - Arrow, 4 folders (Box 6)
    - Avis Rent-A-Car (Box 6)
    - B, miscellaneous (Box 6)
    - Browne and Storch, Inc. (Box 6)
    - The Brundo Art Supply Co. (Box 6)
    - Budget Rent-A-Car (Box 6)
    - C, miscellaneous (Box 6)
    - Cadillac Plastics (Box 6)
    - Chez Bill (Box 6)
    - Chicago Towel Company (Box 6)
    - Clark and Barlow (Box 6)
    - Commonwealth Edison Co. (Box 6)
    - Continental Coffee Co. (Box 6)
    - D, miscellaneous (Box 6)
    - The Drake (Box 6)
    - Dubow Secretarial (Box 6)
    - E, miscellaneous (Box 6)
    - Emery Air Freight (Box 6)
    - F, miscellaneous (Box 6)
    - G, miscellaneous (Box 6)
    - Gaslight Club (Box 6)
    - H, miscellaneous (Box 6)
    - Fred Harvey (Box 6)
    - Hertz Rent-A-Car (Box 7)
    - Hinckley and Schmidt (Box 7)
    - Horders (Box 7)
    - I, miscellaneous (Box 7)
    - Illinois Bell Telephone (Box 7)
    - Illinois Central Railroad (Box 7)
    - International Business Machines (Box 7)
    - J, miscellaneous (Box 7)
    - Ronald P. Johnson (Box 7)
    - K, miscellaneous (Box 7)
    - John P. Kelley (Box 7)
    - The Key Club (Box 7)
    - Kinney Rent-A-Car (Box 7)
    - Kroch's and Brentano's (Box 7)
    - L, miscellaneous (Box 7)
    - LaSalle National Bank (Box 7)
    - Lettering, Inc. (Box 7)
    - M, miscellaneous (Box 7)
    - Merit Photo, 4 folders (Box 7)
    - Monsen, 2 folders (Box 7)
    - N, miscellaneous (Box 7)
    - Near North Guild (Box 7)
    - O, miscellaneous (Box 7)
    - Odman Corporation (Box 7)
    - Old Wells Auto Park (Box 7)
    - P, miscellaneous (Box 7)
    - Brace Pattou and Associates (Box 7)
    - Postmaster of Chicago (Box 7)
    - Pure Oil Company (Box 7)
    - R, miscellaneous (Box 7)
    - Anthony Radavich (Box 7)
    - Railway Express (Box 7)
    - Rosenthal (Box 7)
    - S, miscellaneous (Box 7)
    - Sheldon's, 3 folders (Box 7)
    - Standard Oil, 3 folders (Box 7)
    - Standard Photo (Box 7)
    - T, miscellaneous (Box 7)
    - Joanne Taylor (Box 7)
    - U, miscellaneous (Box 7)
    - V, miscellaneous (Box 7)
    - W, miscellaneous (Box 7)
    - Walruth Whiteprint, Inc. (Box 7)
    - Welna Gallery (Box 7)
    - Western Union (Box 7)
    - Raymond Wielgus, Inc. (Box 7)
    - Xerox Corporation (Box 7)
- Clients correspondence
  - Pierce Adams Agency, 1958 (Box 8)
  - Airguide Instrument Co. (Box 8)
  - Allied Radio Corporation (Box 8)
  - Allied Reports, 1958 (Box 8)
  - A.S. Aloe (Box 8)
  - A.S. Aloe Contract (Box 8)
  - Aluminum Co. of America (Alcoa) (Box 8)
  - Alcoa Contract (Box 8)
  - Aluminum Extrusions, Inc.
    - General correspondence, 1959-1966; 4 folders (Box 8)
    - Board of Director's Meeting (Box 8)
  - American Bank Note Company (Box 8)
  - American Museum of Electronics
    - General correspondence (Box 8)
    - Contract (Box 8)
  - Amron (Box 8)
  - Ansul
    - General correspondence, 1958-1959; 1962-1963; 4 folders (Box 8)
    - General file, 2 folders (Box 8)
  - Archer Daniels Midland
    - General correspondence, 1962-1963; 2 folders (Box 8)
    - General file (Box 8)
  - Argus Inc., 2 folders (Box 9)
  - Arvin Industries (Box 9)
  - Aqua Chem (Box 9)
  - Avon Products (Box 9)
  - Bank of Green Bay, contract (Box 9)
  - Richard Beckhard Associates (Box 9)
  - Bell and Howell
    - General correspondence, 1961-1963; 3 folders (Box 9)
    - Contract (Box 9)
    - Cost File (Box 9)
  - Louis Bernat (Box 9)
  - Blackhawk Manufacturing
    - Aerial survey (Box 9)
    - Development lab (Box 9)
    - General correspondence, 1959 (Box 9)
  - Bollenbach Company (Box 9)
  - Brain Research Foundation (Box 9)
  - Brentwood-General correspondence (Box 9)
  - Burroughs Equipment Co. (Box 9)
  - California Museum of Science and Industry, general correspondence; 4 folders (Box 9)
  - Cantigny Memorial Trust
    - Contract (Box 9)
    - Diagrams (Box 9)
    - Flag frames (Box 9)
    - Memorial Hall (Box 9)
    - Sculptor (Box 9)
  - Carnes Corporation
    - Contract (Box 9)
    - General file, 1958 (Box 9)
    - Invoices, 1958 (Box 9)
  - Celotex Corporation
    - Contract (Box 9)
    - General correspondence (Box 9)
  - Chicago Hardware Foundry (Box 9)
  - Chicago International Fair (Box 9)
  - Chicago Printed String Co. (Box 9)
  - Chicago Tribune (Box 9)
  - Chicken Delight, Inc. (Box 9)
  - Coffee Host, Inc. (Box 9)
  - Continental Bearings (Box 9)
  - Container Corporation of America (Box 9)
  - Corning Glass Works (Box 9)
  - C.P. Electronics, Inc. (Box 9)
  - C. Cretors (Box 9)
  - Culligan
    - General correspondence, 1960-1965; 3 folders (Box 9)
    - General file (Box 10)
    - Market Planning Group, 2 folders (Box 10)
  - Cyprus Mining (Box 10)
  - Dansk (Box 10)
  - Daystrom
    - Correspondence, 1959 (Box 10)
    - General file (Box 10)
    - Market research data, 2 folders (Box 10)
  - Dentists' Supply Company (Box 10)
  - Dole Value Company (Box 10)
  - Dual Jet Refrigeration (Box 10)
  - DuPont De Nemours (Box 10)
  - Dynex Corp. (Box 10)
  - Easterling Company, 4 folders (Box 10)
  - Economics Laboratorie (Box 10)
  - Edwards and Deutsch Lithographing Co. (Box 10)
  - EKCO, 10 folders (Box 10)
  - EKCO, 7 folders (Box 11)
  - Elgin National Watch Co. (Box 11)
  - Evanston Art Center (Box 11)
  - First National Bank of Marinette (Box 11)
  - Florsheim Farms (Box 11)
  - Fostoria Glass Company (Box 11)
  - Franklin Manufacturing Company (Box 11)
  - Garden City Plating and Manufacturing (Box 11)
  - General Electric
    - Budgets (Box 11)
    - Correspondence
      - Bridgeport (Box 11)
      - Louisville (Box 11)
      - Field Enterprises (Box 11)
      - General, 1958-1959; 2 folders (Box 11)
      - Henry Foster (Box 11)
      - Hot Point Division (Box 11)
      - Schenectady, 2 folders (Box 11)
      - Syracuse, 3 folders (Box 11)
      - Utica (Box 11)
    - Crotonville Design Conference (Box 11)
    - General Exhibit and Displays (Box 11)
    - General file (Box 11)
    - General file, 2 folders (Box 12)
    - Report, television (Box 12)
  - Geutings (Box 12)
  - Greeley and Hansen (Box 12)
  - Bank of Green Bay (Box 12)
  - Hallmark Cards (Box 12)
  - Hammond Organ
    - Contract (Box 12)
    - General correspondence, 2 folders (Box 12)
  - Hinson Manufacturing Co. (Box 12)
  - Interstate Vending (Box 12)
  - Jefferson Electric (Box 12)
  - Kettering (Box 12)
  - Kroehler Manufacturing Co. (Box 12)
  - Kuehne Manufacturing Co. (Box 12)
  - LaMere Industries (Box 12)
  - R.S. Landaver (Box 12)
  - Mars (Box 12)
  - The Mengel Furniture Company (Box 12)
  - National Society for Crippled Children and Adults (Box 12)
  - Norman Hoffman Bearings (Box 12)
  - O-Cel-O (Box 12)
  - O'Cedar (Box 12)
  - Jane McCullough (Box 12)
  - Museum of Science and Industry (Box 12)
  - Charles Newman
    - General correspondence (Box 12)
    - Contract (Box 12)
  - Pittsburgh Corning Corp. (Box 12)
  - Playskool Manufacturing (Box 12)
  - Product Presentation, Inc. (Box 12)
  - Profexray, Inc. (Box 12)
  - Rand McNally (Box 12)
  - Ritepoint-Contract (Box 12)
  - Roehr Products (Box 12)
  - Rosenthal
    - Correspondence (Box 12)
    - General file, 4 folders (Box 12)
    - General file, 7 folders (Box 13)
  - Schenectady Museum (Box 13)
  - Arthur Scholder (Box 13)
  - Sealy, Inc. (Box 13)
  - Wesley Sharer and Associates (Box 13)
  - Simplicity Manufacturing Co. (Box 13)
  - Sola Electricity Company (Box 13)
  - Standard meetings
    - General file (Box 13)
    - Correspondence (Box 13)
    - Meetings reports (Box 13)
    - Presentation (Box 13)
    - Research Data-Market (Box 13)
  - Stitzel-Wellor Distillery Company (Box 13)
  - Stonegate China Co. (Box 13)
  - Structural Products, Inc., 6 folders (Box 13)
  - Technical Exhibits (Box 13)
  - Touche, Ross, Bailey and Smart (Box 13)
  - Thomas Industries (Box 13)
  - J. Walter Thompson (Box 13)
  - Clare Udell, Inc. (Box 13)
  - United States Department of Commerce (Box 13)
  - United States Information Agency
    - Construction contracts (Box 13)
    - General correspondence (Box 13)
    - General correspondence, 4 folders (Box 14)
    - Exhibit (Box 14)
  - United States Steel Corporation (Box 14)
  - Universal Training Systems (Box 14)
  - Van Baerle, Inc. (Box 14)
  - Vienna Trade Fair (Box 14)
  - John C. Virden Co. (Box 14)
  - Weber Costello Company (Box 14)
  - Wisconsin Telephone Company (Box 14)
- General correspondence
  - 1958 (Box 14)
  - 1959, 2 folders (Box 14)
  - 1965 (Box 14)
  - 1966 (Box 14)
  - 1967 (Box 14)
- Expense files
  - 1966 (Box 14)
  - 1967 (Box 14)
  - 1968 (Box 14)
- Diaries
  - Berlin Fair (Box 14)